Hey, guys.
大家好
So, what do you think?
你們覺得怎麼樣？
-About what? -What?
-你是指什麼？ -什麼？
Are you kidding? Okay,I'll give you a hint.
你在開玩笑嗎？ 好吧，我給你們一個提示
Eyes.
眼睛
No,no. Your eyes! No.
不，你的眼睛，不
Chandler's eyes!
錢德的眼睛
I got glasses.
我戴上了眼鏡
You always had glasses.
你一直都戴著眼鏡
No, I didn't.
我才沒有
Are you sure?
你確定？
Didn't you have a pair?
以前你沒有戴眼鏡嗎？
They were really round and burgundy, and they made you look kind of...
你戴著圓形酒紅色的眼鏡 看起來有一點…
-Feminine. -Yes!
-娘娘腔 -對
No.
不
I think the glasses look great. You look sexy.
我覺得你很適合戴眼鏡 你看起來很性感
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的嗎？ -對
You didn't think I wore glasses?
你也以為以前我有戴眼鏡嗎？
Of course.
當然不是
The One With Phoebe's Cookies
本集播出：菲比的食譜
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
What do you want for an engagement gift?
你們要什麼訂婚禮物？
That's okay, we're not having a party...
沒關係，我們不辦派對…
so you don't have to get us..
所以你們不必送我們…
If someone wants to give us a present, we can't deprive them of that joy.
如果有人想送我們禮物 我們不該剝奪他們的快樂
You should get them a little CD player.
你應該送他們攜帶型CD機
I already have one.
我已經有一台了
Unless someone borrowed it and left it at the gynecologist.
但有人借走 把它忘在婦產科診所
Yeah, and by "someone" she means Joey.
對，至於「那個人」 她指的是喬伊
I know what I want!
我知道我要什麼
-What we want, honey. -No,you don't want this.
-是我們要什麼，甜心 -不，你不要這個禮物
I want your grandmother's cookie recipe.
我要你奶奶的餅乾食譜
You mean the chocolate chip cookie recipe?
你是說 巧克力碎片餅乾的食譜嗎？
The one my grandma made me swear on her deathbed...
我奶奶臨死前 要我發誓…
that I would never let out of our family?
絕不會洩露給外人的餅乾食譜？
Dying people say the craziest things.
快死的人都會胡言亂語
I've wanted it for years. I was gonna make cookies for my children.
多年來我一直都想得到它 我想幫我的孩子們做餅乾
Break my heart. Oh, all right.
我真的很難過，好吧
I'll be the mom who makes the world's best chocolate chip cookies.
我要當能做出全世界 最好吃餅乾的媽媽
Our kids are gonna be fat, aren't they?
我們的孩子會是胖子，對吧？
Ahoy!
你們好
-How's the boat? -I'm getting into this sailing stuff.
-駕帆船出海還好玩吧？ -我開始喜歡駕駛帆船了
You finally took it out of the marina?
這次你終於出海了？
Why would I do that?
我為什麼要那麼做？
It took three guys to get the thing in there.
三個彪形大漢使出吃奶的力氣 才把它漂在海上
If you don't sail it, what do you do on it?
如果你不想開它出海 你在船上都做些什麼呢？
It's a great place to just sit...
光是坐在那裡就很舒服了…
hang around,drink a few beers, eat some chips.
我什麼都不做，喝啤酒 吃洋芋片
It's good that you finally have a place to do that.
恭喜你終於找到 能那麼做的地方了
I could teach you to sail if you want.
如果你要的話，我可以教你駕駛帆船
-You could? -I've been sailing my whole life.
-你會駕駛帆船？ -我從小就會
When I was 15,my dad bought me my own boat.
我十五歲時 我爸送我一艘帆船
-Your own boat? -He was trying to cheer me up.
-你有一艘帆船？ -他想要安慰我
My pony was sick.
我的小馬生病了
（中央公園咖啡廳）
-You know what I was thinking? -What?
-你知道我在想什麼嗎？ -什麼？
Nothing,I just like to go like this.
沒事，我只是想這麼做
-What are you doing tonight? -Do you have a lecture?
-今晚你要做什麼？ -你有課嗎？
-No, why? -Then, free as a bird. What's up?
-沒有啊，怎麼了？ -那麼我沒事，怎麼了？
My dad wants to know if you want to play racquetball.
我爸想約你去打回力球
Great! Dad must like you!
太棒了，爸一定很喜歡你
He doesn't ask just anyone to play.
他從來不會約人去打回力球
He didn't ask for you. He asked for "Chauncey."
他沒有約你 他要約「小錢」
I assumed he meant you.
我猜他應該是指你
Did you correct him?
你糾正他了嗎？
No,I thought it would be more fun this way.
沒有，我覺得那樣子比較好玩
Cool! Maybe you could do this every week.
太酷了，或許你們每星期都該這麼做
Or you could sit on the porch...
你也可以坐在走廊上…
and make sure no one steals the trashcans.
確定垃圾桶不會被偷走
He does that every week too.
他每星期都會這麼做
Just so you know, you have to let him win. He hates to lose.
你得讓他贏，他最討厭輸了
Maybe I'll play with my left hand.
或許我該用左手打球
You're not a lefty?
你不是左撇子嗎？
Does anybody know me?
有人認識我嗎？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I went to my old apartment to get the cookie recipe...
我到以前的公寓拿餅乾食譜…
and that stupid fire burned it up!
那場愚蠢的大火把它燒了
No! Why didn't you make a copy and keep it in a fireproof box...
不！ 你為什麼沒有影印一份 把它放在防火的盒子裡…
and keep it at least 100 yards away from the original?
將盒子放在離起火點 至少一百碼的地方？
Because I'm normal.
因為我是個凡人
That was the one legacy my grandmother left me.
那是我奶奶留給我的傳奇
And I know you wanted it as an engagement present.
我知道你要它當你的訂婚禮物
We have to get you an engagement present?
我們得送你們訂婚禮物？
Don't worry about it.
別擔心
No one got me an engagement present.
沒有人送我訂婚禮物
I don't have the recipe, but here.
我沒有食譜，但這個給你
I wish you health and happiness.
祝你們健康快樂
An old cookie?
一塊放了很久的餅乾？
This is what happens when you don't register for gifts.
不列出禮物清單 就是會發生這種事
I made a batch and froze it. This is the only one left.
我做了一些餅乾，把它們冷凍起來 這是最後一塊
We can't accept this.
我們不能收下它
Why not?
為什麼？
Cause it's gross.
因為它很噁心
No, wait. I think I can figure out the recipe from this cookie.
不，等一下，我想我可以 利用這塊餅乾猜出整個食譜
I do this at work all the time.
我在工作時常常這麼做
-Really? -I think so!
-真的嗎？ -我想我可以做到
Okay, Ross, we owe you a present.
好吧，羅斯，我們欠你一份禮物
Two! I've been engaged twice.
是兩份，我訂過兩次婚
Look at this clown.
快來看看這個小丑
He thinks he can take up the whole river.
他以為整條河都是他的
Get out of the way, jackass!
別擋路，大混蛋
Who names their boat Coast Guard,anyway?
誰會把自己的船 命名為海岸防衛隊？
That is the Coast Guard.
因為他們就是海岸防衛隊
What are they doing here?
他們在這裡做什麼？
The coast is all the way over there.
海岸在那邊
Joey, just ignore the boats.
喬伊，別管那些船
-We're not finished with our lesson. -All right.
-我們的課還沒有上完 -好吧
I'm gonna go over the basic points once more.
我要幫你複習一下基本要點
Come on,Rach. I got it, okay?
別麻煩了，瑞秋，我已經懂了
I want to go over there...
我想把船開到…
where that boatload of girls is.
那一船小妞旁邊去
Is that it? You want to give...
真的嗎？你想要…
a shout to the hot chicas?
跟那些小妞鬼混？
Okay, let's do that, Sailor Joe.
好了，來吧，水手喬伊
Quick question, though: What's this called?
快問快答，這叫什麼？
-Boat rope? -Wrong!
-船上的繩子？ -錯了
How do you get the mainsail up?
要怎麼把主帆拉上去？
Rub it?
摸一下就行了？
No. What do you do if I say we're coming about?
不，如果我說我們要轉向了 你該怎麼辦？
I say, "Come again?"
我會說：「隨你轉？」
I know this one. I know this one.
我知道，這一題我會
Time's up. Now you're dead.
時間到，現在你死了
And deaf!
我也聾了
You go on and make your little jokes.
你繼續開玩笑吧
If you don't know what you're doing...
如果你不知道自己在做什麼…
you will die. Am I getting through to you?
你就會沒命，你聽懂了嗎？
-Yes. -Don't just say yes.
-懂了 -別只是說你懂了
This isn't a game. You could get hurt out here!
這不是遊戲 你很可能會受傷
Do you want to pay attention, or do you want to die?
你要注意聽我說話 還是想死呢？
I want to make a ship-to-shore call to Chandler.
我想從船上就打電話給錢德
-I definitely taste nutmeg. -You do?
-我吃到了肉豆蔻 -真的嗎？
You don't? Well, that's the difference...
你沒吃到嗎？那就是…
between a professional and a layman.
專業人員跟外行人的不同
That and arrogance.
沒錯，專業人員很傲慢
Hey.
嘿
Hey. How was sailing?
嘿，駕駛帆船出海好玩嗎？
I don't want to talk about it.
我不想談這件事
You could've at least saved me a cookie.
你們至少可以留一塊餅乾給我
Women are mean!
女人太無情了
I can't believe that.
我不敢相信
Now the only thing left of my grandmother's legacy is...
現在我奶奶的傳奇 只剩下…
this crumb.
這塊碎屑
I wish you a long and happy marriage.
祝你們白頭偕老，婚姻美滿
-Hey. -How was it?
-嘿 -怎麼樣？
Well,I had a great time.
我玩得很開心
Chauncey on the other hand...
但是小錢…
I will tell the story.
讓我來說吧
It was going great. I let him win, we were bonding...
我們相處甚歡 我放手讓他贏球，他喜歡我…
he even said I could call him Dad.
甚至說我可以叫他爸爸
And what did he ask you not to call him?
他要你不能叫他什麼？
"Daddy."
爹地
Look,here's the story.
聽著，事情是這樣的
We had just finished playing, and we were gonna take a steam.
我們打完球，決定去做桑拿
I walk into the room...
我走進蒸氣室…
and it's really steamy.
裡面霧氣瀰漫
So I take off my glasses, and that's when it happened.
於是我拿下眼鏡 悲劇發生了
Guys?
你們在哪裡？
-Over here. -Have a seat,son.
-這邊 -坐吧，孩子
Hey!
嘿
-Oh, my God! I can't believe it. -I know.
-我的天啊，我不敢相信 -我知道
You gave my father a lap dance.
你坐在我爸的大腿上
Why do they put so much steam in there?
他們為什麼 要把那裡弄的霧氣瀰漫？
Because otherwise they'd have to call it the "room" room.
不那麼做的話 那裡只能叫做「房間」
Why? Why did that have to happen?
為什麼？ 為什麼會發生那種事？
Come on,it's not that big a deal.
別這樣，那沒有什麼大不了的
Not that big a deal?
那沒有什麼大不了的？
There was touching of things.
我有種異樣的感覺
I know you wanted to bond with my dad...
我知道你想跟我爸打好關係…
but did you have to bond to that part?
但你一定要從他那個地方開始嗎？
I'm sure Dad doesn't care.
我相信爸不會在乎的
He probably thought it was funny.
或許他會覺得很好笑
He'll be telling this story for years.
他會把這個故事掛在嘴邊
I don't want him to tell this story for years.
我就是不希望 他把這個故事掛在嘴邊
Oh,but he will.
他會那麼做的
He still tells the story about how Monica tried to escape from fat camp.
他還是會告訴大家 摩妮卡試圖逃出減肥營的故事
I wasn't escaping.
我才沒有那麼做
Then how'd you get caught in the barbed wire?
那麼你怎麼會 被卡在鐵絲網上的？
I was trying to help out a squirrel.
我想要救一隻松鼠
You were trying to eat it.
你想吃掉他
If that is your father calling to tell this story...
如果是你爸打電話來 告訴你這件事…
then the marriage is off!
那麼我們的婚禮就取消了
Come on. Hello.
別這樣，喂
I'm sorry, you have the wrong number.
對不起，你打錯電話了
I'll call you later, Dad. I love you.
我待會回你電話，爸 我愛你
I'm off to see your dad.
我要去見你爸
Aren't you a little overdressed?
你不會穿太多了嗎？
You better make sure he tips you this time.
你最好確定 這次他會付你小費
I figured I would try to convince him not to tell the story anymore...
我想說服他 別再提那件事…
and I figured the best way to do that was face to face.
我想最好的辦法 就是跟他面對面談一談
And by "face," I don't mean his lap.
我說的「面對面」，指的不是他的大腿
And by "face," I don't mean my ass.
我說的「面對面」，指的不是我的屁股
Are you getting Monica and Chandler a present?
你要送摩妮卡跟錢德禮物？
I don't know. You know, they didn't get us anything.
我不知道 他們沒有送我們禮物
Thank you!
謝謝你
Hey.
嘿
Well,hello.
嗨
So when are we getting back out on the water, matey?
我們什麼時候要再出航？夥伴
I don't know the boat way to say this, but, never.
我不知道水手是怎麼說的 但我死都不要
Why not?
為什麼？
Because you're mean on the boat.
因為你在船上很凶
I was just trying to teach you.
我只是想教會你
Well,lesson learned. Rachel is mean.
我的確學會了教訓 那就是瑞秋很凶
Yep, yep, yep.
對，沒錯
I remember when she took me out on her dad's boat.
我還記得她駕駛她爸的船 帶我出海
She wouldn't let me help at all.
她完全不讓我插手
Excuse me, I wanted you to help.
對不起，我要你幫我
But you couldn't move...
但你連動都動不了…
because you were wearing three life jackets.
因為你穿了三件救生衣
You have to respect the sea.
我們得敬畏大海
Joey,I'm sorry if you thought that was mean.
喬伊，如果你覺得我很凶 對不起
But I tell you, that was not mean.
但我告訴你，我一點都不凶
My father is mean. He used to always yell at me on the boat.
我爸才凶，以前在船上 他總會對我大吼大叫
It was horrible. I was being a really good teacher.
那真的很可怕 我是個很棒的老師
Does a good teacher say, "Put down the beer,pinhead!"
好老師會說： 「把啤酒放下，豬頭」？
Does a good student drink 7 beers during his first lesson?
好學生會在上第一堂課時 喝掉七罐啤酒？
Six and a half.
是六罐半
You knocked the last one out of my hand, remember?
你把最後一罐從我手裡 敲掉，還記得嗎？
I didn't want you to get hit by the boom.
我不希望你被船桅打中
Well,it hit me anyway.
它的確打中我了
It would have hurt a lot less if I had finished that last beer.
如果我能喝完最後一罐啤酒 或許不會那麼痛
I'm sorry. I will try to tone it down and stop yelling.
對不起，我會試著小聲點 不再對你大吼大叫
No bossing me around?
你不會再使喚我？
-I won't boss you around. -And be nice?
-我不會再使喚你 -你會對我很好？
-I'll be nice. -You'll be topless?
-我會對你很好 -你會脫掉上衣？
-Joey! -You want me to learn?
-喬伊 -你希望我學會嗎？
Here's batch 22. Maybe these are like your grandma's.
這是二十二號 或許它們跟你奶奶的餅乾味道很像
This has a bit of orange peel, but no nutmeg.
我放了一些橘子皮 沒有放肉豆蔻
Let's give it a shot.
我們來試吃吧
I haven't made so many cookies since 9th grade.
自從九年級後 我再也沒做過這麼多餅乾
What for, a bake sale?
你為了義賣會做那麼多餅乾嗎？
No, just a Friday night.
不，那是我星期五晚上要吃的
These are pretty good.
這些餅乾真的很好吃
Yeah, but not as good as batch 17.
對，但沒有十七號好吃
Which one was that?
十七號是哪一塊？
The ones we had after you almost threw up.
你幾乎快吐出來後 吃的那塊餅乾
Oh, yeah, batch 17 was good.
對，十七號很好吃
I did not like batch 16.
我不喜歡十六號
I'm okay.
我沒事
Any more from the good batch? We could work off those.
十七號還有剩嗎？ 我們可以好好研究一下
I think there's one left.
我想應該還剩一塊
Batch 16. Sixteen, people, get out of the way!
十六號 這是十六號，別擋路
Okay, Joey. You're doing really good.
喬伊，你表現得很好
I just need you to step to the portside.
我要你站到左舷去
Remember talking about the portside?
還記得左舷是哪一邊嗎？
Oh,yeah.
當然
No.
不
It's left, sweetie, but that's okay. That's a tough one.
是左邊，甜心，但沒關係 那一題太難了
Why not just say left?
為什麼不乾脆說左邊就好了呢？
Okay,go to the left.
好吧，到左邊去
The left.
左邊
Just sit over there!
坐在那邊
You're yelling again. See that?
看到沒？你又在大吼大叫了
Oh,no,no. Very quiet. Said with love, no yelling.
不，我很小聲 語氣充滿了愛意，我沒有大吼大叫
You know what?
你知道了？
Since I'm here,I'm gonna have a beer on the portside.
既然我已經坐在這裡 我要在左舷喝一罐啤酒
See what I did there?
你看到我剛剛做了什麼嗎？
We're luffing a little. Can you tighten up the Cunningham?
風有點大 麻煩你把船繩拉緊
You just said a bunch of stuff I don't know.
你說了一堆我聽不懂的話
Joey,come on! We just went over this.
喬伊，別這樣 我剛剛才教過你
We did that when that bird...
你教我的時候 有隻鳥嘴巴裡…
flew over with the fish in his mouth.
銜著魚飛過去
Did you see it? It was gross.
你看到了嗎？那真的很噁心
I did not see the bird or the fish!
我沒有看到鳥或魚
I did not see the piece of Styrofoam shaped like Mike Tyson!
也沒看到形狀像泰森的保麗龍
I did not, because I was trying to teach you how to sail a boat.
我沒有看到 因為我忙著教你駕駛帆船
Which obviously is an impossible thing to do.
很明顯地 那是不可能的
You're yelling, and I don't see you taking your top off.
你在大吼大叫 而且你沒有脫掉上衣
I quit!
我放棄了
-What do you mean? You can't quit. -Why not?
-你是什麼意思？你不能放棄 -為什麼？
You're not finished! I won't have it. Greenes do not quit.
你還沒有學會，我不准你那麼做 葛林家的人不會放棄
Greenes?
葛林家的人？
I'm a Tribbiani. Tribbianis quit.
我姓崔比亞尼 崔比亞尼家的人會放棄
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
I just said, "Greenes don't quit," didn't I?
剛剛我說 葛林家的人不會放棄，對吧？
Did I say, "Greenes don't quit"?
我到底說了沒有？
Yes! And you're still yelling at me.
對，你還在對我大吼大叫
No,I'm not yelling at you. I'm just yelling near you.
不，我沒有對你大吼大叫 我是對你身邊的空氣大吼大叫
Oh, God, Joey. I'm my father.
天啊，喬伊，我就跟我爸一樣
Oh,my God. This is horrible.
天啊，這真的太可怕了
I try so hard not to be my mother, I didn't see this coming.
我很努力不要跟我媽一樣 卻沒有提防到這一點
I'm so sorry. I just wanted you to learn.
我真的很抱歉 我只希望你能學會駕駛帆船
I did learn.
我的確學會了
-Really? -Yeah, come on.
-真的嗎？ -沒錯，來吧
It's okay.
沒關係的
I know what a mainsail is.
我知道主帆是什麼
I know to duck when the boom comes across.
我知道船桅過來時 一定要低頭
-I know port is right. -Left.
-我知道左舷是右邊 -左邊才對
Damn it!
該死
It would make my grandmother happy...
我們試著研究出她的食譜…
that we're trying to figure out her recipe.
這會讓我奶奶覺得開心
I bet she's looking up at us and smiling right now.
我敢說她正抬頭看著我們 對我們微笑
Looking up?
抬頭看我們？
She was really nice to me but she's in hell for sure.
她對我真的很好 但現在她一定在地獄裡
Well,I've tried everything.
我已經努力過了
I give up. I'm not gonna be the mom...
我放棄，我沒辦法成為…
who makes the world's best cookies.
做出全世界 最好吃餅乾的媽媽
I do make the best duck confit with broccoli raab.
但我會做最好吃的 花椰菜配油封鴨
Kids love that,right?
小孩子很喜歡吃那道菜吧？
Isn't there any relative that has the recipe?
難道你家的親戚 都沒有食譜嗎？
What about your sister?
你妹妹呢？
No. I made a promise to myself that the next time...
不，我跟自己發誓…
I would talk to Ursula is over my dead body.
除非我死掉 不然我不會跟烏蘇拉說話
And that's not happening till October 15,2032.
那一天將會是 2032年10月15日
That's the day you're gonna die?
那天你會死掉？
I've got shuffleboard that day.
那天我要去玩推圓盤遊戲
That's what you think.
你少做夢了
What about friends of your grandma?
你奶奶的朋友呢？
Wouldn't they have the recipe?
他們沒有食譜嗎？
I may have relatives in France who would know.
我在法國的親戚，可能有人知道
My grandmother said she got it from her grandmother, "Nestley Toulouse."
我奶奶說食譜是她奶奶 「鳥巢」傳給她的
What was her name?
她叫什麼名字？
Nestley Toulouse.
鳥巢
Nestle Tollhouse?
雀巢？
You Americans always butcher the French language.
美國人就是 沒辦法說好法文
Phoebe, is this the recipe?
菲比，這是你奶奶的食譜嗎？
Yes!
對
Oh.
喔
I cannot believe that I spent...
我不敢相信…
two days figuring out that recipe.
我花了兩天時間研究那份食譜
It was here the whole time!
結果它一直在這裡
I know! You see, it is stuff like this...
我知道 就是這樣的事情…
which is why you're burning in hell!
害得你得在地獄裡受苦
So you understand.
那麼你懂了
I'd feel better if you didn't tell what happened.
如果你可以不把那件事說出去 我會覺得舒服一點
I'm a little embarrassed about it.
我覺得很不好意思
I understand completely.
我完全瞭解
Nothing's scarier than embarrassing yourself...
最可怕的事莫過於...
in front of your in-laws.
在丈人跟丈母娘面前丟臉
As a matter of fact, when I started dating Judy, I was unemployed.
事實上我開始跟茱蒂交往時 根本就沒有工作
Her father asked me what I did for a living.
她爸問我是幹哪一行的
I said I was a lawyer.
我說我是律師
-What'd you do when they found out? -They never did.
-他們發現事實後你怎麼辦？ -他們一直都沒有發現
So if you ever see me giving them legal advice, just nod along.
如果你看到我在幫他們做法律咨詢 只要點頭就行了
Shall we?
我們可以進去了嗎？
So,I guess we wear swimsuits in here.
我猜這裡得穿泳裝才能進來
Well,Joey,I hate to admit it...
喬伊，我得承認…
your way of sailing is a lot more fun.
你的航海方式 真的有趣多了
Why don't you give a pull on that rope?
你為什麼不拉一下那條繩子？
We're not sailing.
我們沒有要出海
-Just pull on it. -All right.
-拉一下 -好吧
Sandwiches!
三明治
What else?
不然會是什麼呢？
Here you go.
這個給你
-Thank you. -Oh,wow.
-謝謝 -哇
-What are you doing? -Sorry.
-你在做什麼？ -對不起
Not like that. You're letting all the good stuff fall out.
別那樣 好料的都掉在地上了
Careful! You're wasting good pastrami!
小心 你浪費了好吃的醃熏牛肉
Oh,my God. I'm my dad!
天啊，我就跟我爸一樣